S. Makai Takori

Atlanta, GA 30318 | 404-645-0628 | Email | Github | Blog | LinkedIn

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Developer experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and React, with a background in finance and customer service. Experience working independently as well as collaborating in a team setting to strategize, debug, and use object oriented programming to create modern websites and web-based applications.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript | React | Rails | Ruby | ActiveRecord | Sinatra | NPM | Redux | CSS | RESTful Routing | HubSpot | Github | Bootstrap

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Pinterest Clone App - Github | Demo

A clone of the popular Pinterest app that allows users to search for images and favorite ones they want to save

- Built React components using best practices to create front end functionality for better user experience
- Set up Redux to manage and manipulate store state and execute browser routing
- Integrated the Pixabay RESTful API to make async fetch requests for images based on the user's query state

Pseudo Tamagotchi App - Github | Demo

An interactive app where users can create a pet and perform various activities with their new digital companion

- Executed OOJS best practices and events to enhance UX and give users a more interactive experience with their pet
- Employed AJAX to make async fetch requests allowing users to create their own pet that persists to the database
- Implored the use of RESTful Routing utilizing resourceful routes provided by the Ruby on Rails API

Doggy Hotel App - Github | Demo

This application allows users to search for hotels, book, and view reservations with the doggy hotel of their choice

- Established MVC framework, customized CRUD actions, and nested routes using Rails with ActiveRecord ORM
- Implemented sessions and a 3rd party provider using Google's OAuth gem to initiate user authentication

EXPERIENCE

Independent Contractor Lead Website Developer

Remote position 09/2018 - 09/2020

Capstone Alternative Strategies-Website Advantage Consulting, LLC - Website National Black Arts Festival - Website

- Configured website layout and functionality using JavaScript and CSS to build custom templates, modules, and widgets resulting in enhanced user experience based on customer feedback
- Implementation of weekly progress check ins with the project manager, UX designer, and/or client promoting transparency and open communication
- Responsible for debugging and troubleshooting to find solutions to varying website errors

Benefit Wealth Administration

Atlanta, GA

Loan Administrator

09/2014 - 03/2019

- Calculated and managed 160+ loan/receivable accounts for clients on a monthly basis ensuring that each report was accurate, up-to-date, and could be easily accessible to the client
- Delivered monthly receivable reports to over 150 clients based on the monthly AFR rates resulting in consistent onboarding of new clients

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, and React program

Online Program 12/2019 - 10/2020

Oglethorpe University Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Psychology Atlanta, GA 08/2010